[SPEAKER_04]: It says you're born in Steubenville, September 30th, 1885?
[SPEAKER_04]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_03]: That makes you how old now?
[SPEAKER_03]: Ninety-four.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ninety-four?
[SPEAKER_04]: Wow.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, what I like to do in these interviews, just ask you, you know, where you grew up and
[SPEAKER_04]: Where you grew up, what your family did you know, and how you broke into baseball, just a little bit of family history.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's always very interesting to me.
[SPEAKER_04]: So if you could just start it, and what your dad did, and how you got into playing baseball.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's all yours.
[SPEAKER_03]: I love baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know you have to have a desire in baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's what, Reardon Cobb was a great ball player.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a desire.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wanted to, if you shoot him, he wanted to shoot better than anybody else.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wanted to play golf better.
[SPEAKER_04]: What'd your dad do?
[SPEAKER_03]: He play ball?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a glass worker.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was a glass worker, so I had to either quit playing or quit working, so I quit working.
[SPEAKER_01]: What glass company did you work for?
[SPEAKER_03]: I worked for a head of the glass company in Danville, Illinois.
[SPEAKER_03]: I learned my trade there, glass working.
[SPEAKER_03]: How long did you live in Steubenville?
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just lived maybe a year or two or something like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Your family moved then to Danville?
[SPEAKER_03]: My family moved up around Lazerville, West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then moved to Indiana.
[SPEAKER_03]: I moved to Indiana when I was five years old.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I was raised in Indiana.
[SPEAKER_03]: What town?
[SPEAKER_03]: Anderson.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Carl Erskine country.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: There would only have been about three or four when I was going out of there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, you don't have too many remembrances of Steubenville then.
[SPEAKER_04]: Okay, did you go to school in Anderson then?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did they have a team, a ball team at school?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, yeah, we had a baseball club.
[SPEAKER_04]: Where did you play your first professional ball?
[SPEAKER_03]: I played my first professional ball
[SPEAKER_04]: Paris, Illinois.
[SPEAKER_04]: When was that, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_03]: 1970.
[SPEAKER_03]: What league was that in?
[SPEAKER_03]: Eastern Illinois League.
[SPEAKER_03]: Little Class D League.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who signed you, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_03]: To a contract?
[SPEAKER_03]: Bob Connery.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was in St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was signed to a Cardinal contract.
[SPEAKER_03]: Where did he see you play?
[SPEAKER_03]: Some of me play in Texas.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was playing with Waco, Texas.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was one of the few fellows in those days that made it good right from the start.
[SPEAKER_04]: How did you happen to be in Texas?
[SPEAKER_03]: I signed a contract with
[SPEAKER_03]: Decatur, Illinois, and the lake blew up on 4th of July, and I went to Columbia, South Carolina.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was a South Atlantic lake.
[SPEAKER_03]: Played there, and then in Edison, 12, 12.
[SPEAKER_03]: Grew up in 13.
[SPEAKER_03]: Went from Columbia up to the Cardinals?
[SPEAKER_03]: I went to the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was there for four years.
[SPEAKER_04]: Who managed the Cardinals when you went up there?
[SPEAKER_04]: Miller Huggins.
[SPEAKER_03]: How did you like Miller Huggins?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, fine.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was smart.
[SPEAKER_03]: We didn't get along too good, but he was a great manager.
[SPEAKER_03]: He knew his baseball.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was one of the baseball greats.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had a reason for doing everything he did.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now they don't, too many of them, have a reason for doing some of it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Just take a chance.
[SPEAKER_04]: Was Huggins a pretty good handler of men?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: He couldn't handle Babe Ruth, I know, but I wondered about generally speaking.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, Babe had a bunch of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm just trying to think of the ones that were bad.
[SPEAKER_04]: Who were some of the players on the team for the Cardinals that year you went up?
[SPEAKER_04]: Remember?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bill Doak, he was from Ohio.
[SPEAKER_04]: I'm just trying to think of some of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Not too many from Ohio.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, Sallee.
[SPEAKER_04]: Slim?
[SPEAKER_03]: Slim Sallee.
[SPEAKER_04]: Slim Sallee.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was on there in Maranthas, Maryland.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think we have a fellow named Brower going on there, too.
[SPEAKER_04]: Frank Brower?
[SPEAKER_04]: In your first basement, I believe.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I believe Dick Niehaus was from Ohio.
[SPEAKER_04]: This was at the winter baseball meeting?
[SPEAKER_03]: Beg your pardon?
[SPEAKER_01]: The winter baseball meeting?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, winter in December.
[SPEAKER_03]: Our meeting was in
[SPEAKER_03]: in Toronto this last year, and before that in Orlando.
[SPEAKER_04]: That was nice and handy.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Eddie Rouse get to the one in Orlando?
[SPEAKER_03]: I was over there, in the Crownery over there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Who were some of your
[SPEAKER_04]: How'd the team do that first year up with the Cardinals in 1913?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you remember how?
[SPEAKER_03]: We finished third in fourteen.
[SPEAKER_03]: Were you up with the team most of that year?
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a bad leg.
[SPEAKER_03]: Two years on a bad knee.
[SPEAKER_03]: Two years on each knee.
[SPEAKER_04]: How'd that happen?
[SPEAKER_03]: sliding and sliding into me and stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_03]: You played at the side.
[SPEAKER_03]: You played shortstop?
[SPEAKER_03]: I played third race, mostly.
[SPEAKER_04]: Some shortstop.
[SPEAKER_04]: You get spiked quite a few times there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Not so much.
[SPEAKER_03]: It seems though I had trouble.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had an attachment right here on the side of the knee.
[SPEAKER_03]: Left knee, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: And it hit you on the side.
[SPEAKER_04]: You have to learn to get that foot out of there in a hurry.
[SPEAKER_04]: Who played shortstop?
[SPEAKER_03]: Gordon Butler.
[SPEAKER_04]: And second base?
[SPEAKER_03]: Huggins played second.
[SPEAKER_04]: Oh, he was a playing manager, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: part of the year and then he quit.
[SPEAKER_04]: In 1914, you played most of the season, 137 games in 1914, playing both third and mostly third.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I was out with a bad knee in about a month.
[SPEAKER_04]: Who owned the Cardinals?
[SPEAKER_03]: A fellow named Robertson.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you ever meet him or talk to him?
[SPEAKER_04]: What kind of a guy was he?
[SPEAKER_04]: This was Frank Robinson?
[SPEAKER_03]: You know him a little better than you know him now.
[SPEAKER_03]: There were two brothers, weren't there?
[SPEAKER_03]: Stanley and Frank.
[SPEAKER_03]: His wife really owned the town.
[SPEAKER_03]: What kind of money did they pay you?
[SPEAKER_03]: Most I got out of the Major League was $4,000.
[SPEAKER_04]: That was fairly good money.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you have any contract troubles at all?
[SPEAKER_04]: You never held out too long.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you get a letter during the winter with your contract in it?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Where'd you live those winters?
[SPEAKER_03]: I lived in St. Louis a couple of years.
[SPEAKER_04]: You played 1915 and 1916, you played about half a season.
[SPEAKER_04]: Were you injured then?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: bad knees.
[SPEAKER_03]: They didn't operate on you in those days like they do now.
[SPEAKER_03]: We've had ball players operate on four or five times their knees.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you ever go to Bowen Center, Reese?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, but I know a lot about him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a steel worker.
[SPEAKER_03]: He had strong hands.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I played in California in 1919, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_03]: There was an osteopath named Spencer.
[SPEAKER_03]: I went to him.
[SPEAKER_03]: My back was bad.
[SPEAKER_03]: I went to Spencer in L.A. And Spencer told me that the old fellow had torn a ligament in
[SPEAKER_03]: And, uh, whose arm?
[SPEAKER_03]: One of the two fellows explained me the total ligament in his arm was strong.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't know anything about treating ballplayers.
[SPEAKER_01]: And how about if ballplayers went to him?
[SPEAKER_04]: We talked to a number of players in the Cleveland area, like George Ewing and Walter Miller.
[SPEAKER_04]: They said it got to be quite comical.
[SPEAKER_04]: They began talking about fat arms, and I mentioned Bonesetter Reese.
[SPEAKER_03]: Spencer told me the scar tissue was there to show that he did tear.
[SPEAKER_03]: That Reese did?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He did some damage then.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He told them it'd be alright in a week, and in a week he couldn't raise his arm.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bill Killifer was one of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Catcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Big Ed Walsh.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: Big Ed Walsh.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ruined it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I think it would have.
[SPEAKER_03]: gotten around, they wouldn't have gotten him so much.
[SPEAKER_04]: How is it batting against Christy Matheson?
[SPEAKER_03]: I never had so much trouble against Matheson.
[SPEAKER_03]: Matheson, he was a... You know, now, the balls are pepped up.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: 30% more, at least 30% more.
[SPEAKER_03]: And...
[SPEAKER_03]: With the hard top, with that black top on there, you know, they have to use that.
[SPEAKER_03]: It makes it that much harder.
[SPEAKER_03]: It just changed so much that you wouldn't think it'd change.
[SPEAKER_04]: So, does the dead ball really help pitchers like Matheson, then?
[SPEAKER_04]: They're pretty good anyhow.
[SPEAKER_03]: Madison never, he was a type of pitcher that never pitched hard until he got men on.
[SPEAKER_03]: But now, with that lively ball now, you can't take that chance, you see.
[SPEAKER_03]: You're playing with ballparks at 315 feet from home plate to the fence.
[SPEAKER_03]: Kick the coconut over that.
[SPEAKER_04]: How about Rube Marquardt?
[SPEAKER_04]: About against him much?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember I got four hits off of Rube.
[SPEAKER_03]: You did?
[SPEAKER_03]: Tell me about it.
[SPEAKER_03]: First game I ever...
[SPEAKER_04]: That's a nice looking scrapbook.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you keep that yourself?
[SPEAKER_04]: Scrapbook?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, I did.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's from right after the last runner.
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you have any duplicate copies of any of these?
[SPEAKER_04]: Do you have any second copies or duplicates of any of these?
[SPEAKER_04]: Is it nice?
Finally closed.
Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_04]: You got four hits off Marquardt, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, if I can find them.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was managing a minor league club one time.
[SPEAKER_03]: They get all messed up here.
[SPEAKER_03]: I never paid much attention to these until lately.
[SPEAKER_01]: We saw Rube Marquardt in the summer.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, last August we saw Rube Marquardt up in Baltimore.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was just on his way going up to the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_04]: He wasn't well though, so I don't know how he made out.
[SPEAKER_03]: They're back in there someplace.
[SPEAKER_04]: Tell me about it as you remember it though, that day against Marquardt there.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember I got four hits on him.
[SPEAKER_03]: I got four hits off of him the first game we ever played against him.
[SPEAKER_03]: He laughed.
[SPEAKER_03]: I had to get him a book to show him.
[SPEAKER_04]: Before it's out, Mark Roy, first game you played against him.
[SPEAKER_04]: I have here a list of players he sent to the major leagues.
[SPEAKER_04]: Jake Early, Gil Cohn, Jimmy Bloodworth, Tony Roig, Ed Linkey, Ray Scarborough, John Marion, Earl Wooden, Dean Miles,
[SPEAKER_04]: Leon Pettit, Phil Andrews, Cecil Travis, Sam Holbrook, Ray Phoebus, Kirby Hayes, and Goose Gosling.
[SPEAKER_01]: You have quite an impressive list there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Jackie Tavener, Will Seymour.
[SPEAKER_04]: It is a list.
[SPEAKER_03]: I guess I'd really send more
[SPEAKER_03]: players up than any other scout.
[SPEAKER_03]: You've been scouting?
[SPEAKER_03]: You scouted for 48 years, was it?
[SPEAKER_03]: I still scout.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you'll have to come to Marietta.
[SPEAKER_03]: I picked a boy up two years ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: What was his name?
[SPEAKER_03]: They made him, uh... As you get older, I feel more lately than any other time, forgetful.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll have that stage one of these days, I guess.
[SPEAKER_04]: He's up to the big legs you mean now?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he was a rookie of the year.
[SPEAKER_04]: Just last year?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Which is late now.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, wow.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: Good now.
[SPEAKER_04]: I can't remember.
Here's the one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Does he play for Minnesota, the boy?
[SPEAKER_00]: Ma'am?
[SPEAKER_01]: Does the rookie of the year play for Minnesota, the one you just sent up?
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm a little hard of hearing.
[SPEAKER_01]: This chap that you just sent up, who does he play for?
[SPEAKER_03]: Twins.
[SPEAKER_01]: Twins.
[SPEAKER_03]: All right.
[SPEAKER_03]: Made good right from the start.
[SPEAKER_01]: Isn't that nice?
[SPEAKER_01]: Gratifying.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, we have a, they play the Class AAA, or Class AAA.
[SPEAKER_04]: Division III.
[SPEAKER_01]: Division III.
[SPEAKER_01]: College Series, World Series at Marietta every year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: And we never can understand why there aren't more scouts at it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they just don't seem to...
[SPEAKER_00]: I think on a last year's World Series, they only drafted one person.
[SPEAKER_01]: And yet, you know, Kent... Kent Dichovy, the... pirate pitcher?
[SPEAKER_03]: Pirate pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: Pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: The relief pitcher?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He went to Marietta.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, he did?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was never drafted.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wasn't.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, I don't see it yet.
[SPEAKER_04]: Can you remember the batting against Marquardt, getting those hits?
[SPEAKER_04]: Must have been quite a thrill, huh?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I haven't paid any attention to it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Just now I'm having something like this come up.
[SPEAKER_04]: What was your best day?
[SPEAKER_04]: Was that your best day in the big leagues?
[SPEAKER_03]: I just said it was.
[SPEAKER_04]: Have any other good days?
[SPEAKER_04]: Here it is.
[SPEAKER_04]: Right here.
[SPEAKER_04]: Four out of four.
[SPEAKER_04]: Two runs scored.
[SPEAKER_04]: You made an error though.
[SPEAKER_04]: Three outs, three assists.
[SPEAKER_04]: Your pitcher was Parrott.
[SPEAKER_04]: Powell, Parrott, and Robinson.
[SPEAKER_04]: That was a good giant team, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_04]: George Burns, Larry Doyle, Snodgrass, Myers, Bescher, Jim Thorpe.
[SPEAKER_04]: It doesn't give the date on it, though.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's June 5th.
[SPEAKER_04]: Who were some of the tougher pitchers you had to face?
[SPEAKER_03]: Offhand, I'd have to see their names.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, a pitcher named Cantalina was tough.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was kind of a perky jerky.
[SPEAKER_03]: He gave me more trouble than anybody else.
[SPEAKER_03]: Who was he with?
[SPEAKER_04]: Check him out.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was with Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_04]: How about Grover Cleveland Alexander?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I hit against him a lot.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was a great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: Real good control.
Very interesting.
Well, uh,
[SPEAKER_04]: How'd you like the umpires?
[SPEAKER_03]: All right.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember when they worked a single system.
[SPEAKER_03]: One umpire?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I remember in 1895, I saw him in Cincinnati play, and
[SPEAKER_03]: The catcher stayed back for the grandstand so he got two strikes on the hitter or a man on the first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: Then he'd go up and put the mattress down.
[SPEAKER_04]: When there was just one umpire, did the players sometimes cut second base?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I've seen them cut right straight across.
[SPEAKER_04]: Four umpires.
[SPEAKER_04]: Now they have six of them, or four of them.
[SPEAKER_04]: World Series has six.
[SPEAKER_04]: Did you serve in World War I?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_04]: I noticed you played at 16 but not at 17, and then a little bit at 18 with the Yankees.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I jumped to anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: But you were in the war, in the army?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, no, I wasn't.
[SPEAKER_03]: I was just over the edge on the drive.
[SPEAKER_03]: I see.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I thought I ought to do something, and I went over in a steel mill.
[SPEAKER_03]: And after I got over there, I was sorry because people walk around there with a wrench in their hand and just walk around and not do anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was working on a 10%
[SPEAKER_03]: He was leading the league when he left, and he was leading the league when he came.
[SPEAKER_03]: And when he left, he was two games out in the front.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I beat him one penalty that year.
[SPEAKER_03]: And the thing that hurt him most was
[SPEAKER_03]: I had a outfielder that we released and I signed up and I sold him for $7,500 for the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he was, uh, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: But obviously, something... Now, whether it was his mind or that... Because, you know, we were sitting talking, just the way we are.
[SPEAKER_02]: And all of a sudden, he said, uh... What'd he say you were?
[SPEAKER_02]: So we told him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said, what newspaper are you with?
[SPEAKER_02]: My husband said, I'm not with any newspaper.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm a college professor.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't talk to newspaper reporters.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't have anything to do with it, including doctors anymore.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we got up and left.
[SPEAKER_02]: And the nurse said, oh, don't.
[SPEAKER_02]: You'll be all right.
[SPEAKER_02]: But we didn't.
[SPEAKER_02]: We thought at that point we'd better get off.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, you know, he apparently, but it was newspaper reporters he had written about, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: But, you know, everything was going along very nicely, so, all of a sudden, he's arrested.
[SPEAKER_02]: And, you know, he was told he was a college professor.
[SPEAKER_02]: He is really just like me.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he's a man.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we just, we said, now he was on his way to the Hall of Fame, and it must be, whether it was his wife's son, someplace along the line, a step-son, was flying in from London to go up to Cooperstown with him when we were there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because I didn't see how he was going to make it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't, I don't know if I, if I would go there, but anyway, I don't think he ever had money.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, boy either that or Marion I Didn't say that but you know, it was one of these big plus apartment complexes and everything was done Blue carpets on that everything was done in blue and white with big black furniture it was an I mean, you know, I
[SPEAKER_02]: It was almost a showcase rather than a place that people live in.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, he worked at the race track.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I think he told us that.
[SPEAKER_03]: He worked at the race track.
[SPEAKER_03]: So beautiful.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, well, whatever he did, it came from someplace.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know where his money's coming from.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know either, but he, because I was, it was one of the, you know, almost every ball player we visited, their house was like our house.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, a nice, comfortable house.
[SPEAKER_02]: But this was, as I say, almost like a showcase.
[SPEAKER_02]: with velvet covers on all the furniture in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're covered in velvet.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it was, it was just different back then.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had a ground floor apartment and the whole one end was, and I'm sure the living room was as wide as this house.
[SPEAKER_02]: They knew the apartment, the basement.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we had a Christmas card there from Kovaleski, Dan Kovaleski, the picture.
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess they made it up to Cooperstown this year, they said.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I don't know how old he is.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, our club, we stayed in second place all season.
[SPEAKER_03]: the last six, seven games, and we lost by a lot of things, and we went out second place in the box.
[SPEAKER_03]: And Calvin Griffin told me, he said, the Bears have been crying around about money, and he said, when they had a chance to finish second, which was several thousand dollars, that meant it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Doesn't Bob Randall play for Minnesota?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is there a Bob Randall?
[SPEAKER_02]: Their second baseman?
[SPEAKER_02]: He worked down in Marietta one winter.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he was over at the house with the Colby.
[SPEAKER_02]: And another boy that was at the college called Tatum, who was a bonus baby for some Oakland.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he went to school in the fall and then took every spring off.
[SPEAKER_02]: But by the time he graduated, it took him eight years to get that degree.
[SPEAKER_02]: But then he lost his job and he's out of it now.
[SPEAKER_02]: But Marietta has, I think now they have three quarters of the college itself that have been
[SPEAKER_02]: They have a picture named Tice down in Atlanta.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, he's not, he's with our farm team.
[SPEAKER_02]: But they had a non, he had an arm op or a shoulder operation in June, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then another couple of boys coming up, uh, uh Tracy.
[SPEAKER_02]: I forget who the other one is.
[SPEAKER_02]: But it's a good baseball town for college ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: They always have good teams down there.
[SPEAKER_02]: They may not take you.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I'm 94.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can't go a whole lot longer.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think you're remarkable.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's embarrassing.
[SPEAKER_03]: You know, I forget so many things.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't see why.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just forget walking from one room to another.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I can...
[SPEAKER_03]: I know I have part in the...
[SPEAKER_03]: One nice thing about the whole thing is I won't be tied up so long.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, that's true.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I think it's remarkable that you can get around and do as much as you can.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, I think that's the beauty of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: We have people who, we live in a little town across the river from Marietta, Williamstown.
[SPEAKER_02]: And when we moved down this street that we live on now, there were four people 100 years old on it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they were all out working in their garden and these things.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, they just worked up a storm.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I thought, boy, how'd the light pull this?
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, to be able to keep on going like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can't do it.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think we need to get out to the ballpark in the summer and that thing.
[SPEAKER_02]: We haven't paid.
[SPEAKER_03]: They call me now and then and ask me and tell me they want me to pass on somebody.
[SPEAKER_03]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_03]: On the last year.
[SPEAKER_03]: They told me they wanted me to pass on.
[SPEAKER_03]: The rest of the children passed on.
[SPEAKER_03]: What do you look for?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I look for alarms.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the first thing I look for is a good alarm, because if he has a good alarm, he may be able to play anything.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now, now, they don't put their first baseman into the play ball much.
[SPEAKER_03]: So if he's been hit by it, they put him in first base.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you have a pitcher to help him and a second baseman to help him to a certain extent.
[SPEAKER_03]: What about speed?
[SPEAKER_03]: About speed?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: If you don't have speed, you can't call it anything.
[SPEAKER_04]: What if they can only hit?
[SPEAKER_04]: Now that we have the designated hitter, does that color your thinking a little bit now?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you can learn to hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: I can show you in my own averages that I learned to hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: You got to keep writing those books over there.
[SPEAKER_04]: How did you learn?
[SPEAKER_03]: You yourself?
[SPEAKER_03]: By watching other people?
[SPEAKER_03]: We were standing, I went, I started to manage the ball club.
[SPEAKER_03]: In Columbia, South Carolina.
[SPEAKER_03]: And we were standing there one day, and there was a boy, a player, a player there.
[SPEAKER_03]: He said, Dolly Stark says, hold the back of me rigid.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hold your back of me rigid.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I thought I'd try.
[SPEAKER_03]: And it made me hit it out of me.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hit that one thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because my weight was back, you see.
[SPEAKER_03]: And when I made my right leg rigid, I had to put weight all on that, see.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I hit then, I hit...
[SPEAKER_03]: Johnson led the American League in hitting, and he out hit me in two years, just about 3 or 4 points.
[SPEAKER_03]: In two years.
[SPEAKER_03]: He hit 3.16 and 3. .
[SPEAKER_03]: .
[SPEAKER_03]: 3.12, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then the next year he hit
[SPEAKER_03]: 290 and I hit 383.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now that's what I'm thinking of mine from.
[SPEAKER_03]: What I did when I... Who were you with?
[SPEAKER_03]: I was a 9th and 20th in a minor league.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why did Miller Huggins tell you these things?
[SPEAKER_04]: There's somebody up in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, you never know.
[SPEAKER_03]: You never know because
[SPEAKER_03]: Hug used to say to me, so you hit like Bobby Burns.
[SPEAKER_03]: So I couldn't hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he'd go a couple weeks and he'd say, all right, now try to hit like somebody else.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd have me ask three or four different people there that he'd want me to pattern after.
[SPEAKER_03]: And finally I couldn't hit her anymore.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did well enough for all of them.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did it hurt your confidence doing this?
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I don't believe so.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just figured I wasn't a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then I got to hitting.
[SPEAKER_04]: Over 340 for 12 years as manager.
[SPEAKER_04]: 32, right?
[SPEAKER_02]: Uh, a fine fellow.
[SPEAKER_02]: Geek guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Saw him play many times.
[SPEAKER_03]: He really could...
[SPEAKER_02]: Everybody hits the ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: That can help them get them in because it's always hard to get in.
He's taking over the field.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had a lot of things going on out there.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had about 53 cars last year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why?
[SPEAKER_02]: Their problem is this school, though.
[SPEAKER_03]: Aren't they?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, it's surprising the number of colleges that come down here every year.
[SPEAKER_03]: At least dead four a week.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I know that's what Marietta does.
[SPEAKER_02]: They come down, but as I say, I think they must go.
[SPEAKER_03]: They've got a beautiful setup out here.
[SPEAKER_03]: They've got three or four fields out there.
[SPEAKER_03]: It's a big field.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was shady anyway.
[SPEAKER_04]: They used to have a team here though, didn't they?
[SPEAKER_04]: A professional team?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, we came in here as a tiny little...
[SPEAKER_03]: Tiny little club.
[SPEAKER_03]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_03]: Like six years ago.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, six years ago?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, six years ago.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_04]: Well, here we are It's Monday night December 31st 1979 New Year's Eve And we're holed up in our little room a big room in a day motel or excuse me Dave in South of Orlando, Florida
[SPEAKER_04]: We drove down from Williamstown last Thursday, December 27th.
[SPEAKER_04]: Spent the night in Rock Hill, South Carolina.
[SPEAKER_04]: Drove on to St. Augustine on Friday, December 28th.
[SPEAKER_04]: Stayed at a KOA campground between St. Augustine and Jacksonville that night.
[SPEAKER_04]: Spent Saturday, December 29th touring historic St. Augustine.
[SPEAKER_04]: Wonderful day.
[SPEAKER_04]: stayed in the campground again that night and on Saturday morning, December 30th, Sunday morning on the 30th, we also spent seeing some things we had not yet seen in St. Augustine and in the afternoon drove down to Sanford where we spent the night last night at the 12 Oaks campground a few miles outside of Sanford, Florida.
[SPEAKER_04]: And this morning, earlier, to back up on
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes, Sunday, yesterday afternoon after we got around Sanford, I called up Zinbeck and inquired if we could come and see him for an interview this morning and he was very agreeable.
[SPEAKER_04]: So we set the interview up for 10 o'clock this morning, December 31st.
[SPEAKER_03]: So we broke camp, got up early about 6 o'clock or 5 o'clock or 4 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was dark and we got everything put away, sat around and read the paper until the place opened up.
[SPEAKER_04]: Then went into town, into Sanford, about 9 o'clock, had breakfast and then was there about a half hour.
[SPEAKER_04]: Then drove out to Zinbeck's house, got there a little before 10 and had this interview, which I have to admit was not much of an interview.
[SPEAKER_04]: He's a very gracious old gentleman who is
[SPEAKER_04]: Ninety-four years old, despite some clippings I have, he would say he's ninety-five.
[SPEAKER_04]: Born on September 30, 1885.
[SPEAKER_04]: He'd be ninety-four now.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's in his ninety-fifth year, as you would say.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yes, he is in his ninety-fifth year, but he's ninety-four, as you would say.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_04]: He just didn't have much to say.
[SPEAKER_04]: His memory wasn't too
[SPEAKER_04]: good, which he apologized for several times, and he did follow up on some of the things he was started on.
[SPEAKER_04]: I did most of the talking.
[SPEAKER_04]: He's obviously on the tape, but I'm tired of hearing myself talk on these tapes.
[SPEAKER_04]: But at least we did talk to Zinbeck and got a little feel of his personality and his love of baseball.
[SPEAKER_04]: We got his autograph on the baseball.
[SPEAKER_04]: We've got some clippings about him from local newspapers which have honored him on every one of his 90-plus birthdays, getting a rocking chair out at the Orlando Baseball Complex, although it's in Sanford.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was given this chair.
[SPEAKER_04]: We have a picture of it.
[SPEAKER_04]: on his 91st birthday, which was back in 1976, and each year they changed the number to 92, 93, and it had on it today when you're out there, 94.
[SPEAKER_04]: In fact, I took a picture of him in it with the 94 showing, I think.
[SPEAKER_04]: He's in Beck's chair.
[SPEAKER_04]: Why don't you tell us about his house now?
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, we were only in the one room, but it was that small,
[SPEAKER_00]: One-story house.
[SPEAKER_00]: The living room was a good size.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd say it was probably, oh, maybe 15 by 15.
[SPEAKER_00]: The living room was quite large because he had a television set and he had a big chair, rocker chair, a big chair that he sat in.
[SPEAKER_00]: I sat in a big leather chair.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then he had two other big chairs and a sofa in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And one wall had all his baseball things on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And off that room was a dining room.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then off at the other door went into a bedroom.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he may have just bought that, you know, after his wife died or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you find out when his wife died?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: All he said was there were only the two of them left, the three of them left.
[SPEAKER_00]: himself, his daughter, and her son.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, there's a picture, there was a picture of the daughter on the wall with two children, so obviously something must have happened to the other one.
[SPEAKER_00]: The son is a stockbroker in Miami and has one daughter, so he has a great-granddaughter.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the house is very nicely furnished.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were traverse rods
[SPEAKER_04]: Not very pretentious from the outside.
[SPEAKER_00]: But some beautiful things on the inside.
[SPEAKER_00]: That fish was lovely.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was on the mantel.
[SPEAKER_04]: Get a picture of the 1914 St. Louis Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_04]: One of those long panoramic pictures where the player is standing in a long single row on one wall, which I tried to take pictures of in segments but I could not get the right lighting on it.
[SPEAKER_04]: I'm sure it will be very poor.
[SPEAKER_04]: And also another wall, the 1915 Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_04]: himself in both of these pictures and again a long single row.
[SPEAKER_04]: I didn't bother to even try to take that one.
[SPEAKER_04]: There are two other pictures on the wall which I did take pictures of.
[SPEAKER_04]: One was himself and the other one was himself but with a different head of himself on a different picture of himself, if you understand what I mean.
[SPEAKER_04]: It still looked like himself though.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or was that his body, too, on that other one?
[SPEAKER_04]: It was himself, I think.
[SPEAKER_04]: They somehow... Superimposed another head on it.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was very well done because you wouldn't have noticed it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he had...
[SPEAKER_00]: There was one from Charlotte, a certificate or trophy or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was one from Sanford, Florida.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was one from Chattanooga.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was one from Steubenville.
[SPEAKER_04]: These are framed certificates of merit or honor, awards given to him as outstanding contributors to the sports and well-being of these cities.
[SPEAKER_04]: There was one from Steubenville.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had his crown there.
[SPEAKER_04]: That crown, as you may have heard in the tape, was put on him probably by Bowie Coon at the 1978 Major League Winter Meetings held in Orlando.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was, because he has his picture taken with Gould there.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was just a nice little old man.
[SPEAKER_00]: And as he says, he knows he has hardening of the arteries, but he figures then when it really happens, he won't have very long to go in a debilitated stage.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he regrets his memory.
[SPEAKER_00]: He is having trouble with it, and he admits it.
[SPEAKER_04]: He was a wonderful gentleman.
[SPEAKER_04]: nice and pleasant as could be, but he didn't have much to say.
[SPEAKER_04]: There was so much he could say, but he wasn't able, I suppose he was inhibited by his not being able to recall some things, couldn't hear some things.
[SPEAKER_04]: Much of the interview may sound kind of irrelevant, but was centered around a scrapbook, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_04]: I kept switching the thing off when he was looking through
[SPEAKER_04]: One of the problems was I would mention things and he would go off to bring back something or to point out pictures.
[SPEAKER_04]: Like when I asked about who the teammates were in the 1914 Cardinals, he vanished and went over to look at that picture on the wall and began reading off a few names.
[SPEAKER_04]: And then I mentioned something else, he went for his scrapbook, so there was an awful lot of dead air there I'm sure.
[SPEAKER_04]: The scrapbook was kept by himself and it covers
[SPEAKER_04]: Much of his playing career, he must have quit playing in the late 20s.
[SPEAKER_04]: He said he managed 12 years, and I guess he played most of those years, scouting for 40-some years.
[SPEAKER_04]: I'd go back to about 1930 or so.
[SPEAKER_04]: So I suspect he finished playing in the late 20s or early 30s.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, because they said it's 73 continuous years in baseball, and he's been with that one
[SPEAKER_00]: organization for 47 years.
[SPEAKER_04]: The old Washington Senators and the Minnesota Twins.
[SPEAKER_04]: The scrapbook wasn't that elaborate, but it had some nice things in it.
[SPEAKER_04]: I took a lot of pictures of the newspaper pictures of him in there, which I'm afraid aren't going to be much.
[SPEAKER_04]: I don't know what trouble with the lighting that I've ever had before in that camera.
[SPEAKER_04]: I thought the lighting was good,
[SPEAKER_04]: I had to switch the speed down to 30 instead of 60, and at that speed you have to hold that camera awfully steady, and I felt shaken.
[SPEAKER_04]: But anyhow, I got some clippings of him, as I mentioned, pertaining to his 91st, 2nd, 3rd, 4th, and so on birthdays, which has a little bit of his biography in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had all the record books from 1900 on.
[SPEAKER_04]: Baseball guides, Reach.
[SPEAKER_04]: I know he had Reach and I think he had Spalding, too.
[SPEAKER_04]: Maybe not Spalding.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had Blue Books going way back.
[SPEAKER_04]: He had the Reach guides up until they finished and then the Sporting News guides.
[SPEAKER_04]: He had Baseball Registers since they came out in 1940.
[SPEAKER_04]: A lot of Blue Books from about 1940s or 50s.
[SPEAKER_04]: when he was heavy in scouting.
[SPEAKER_00]: Although he said he sent up the player last year who in 1979 won the Rookie of the Year award in the American League and I can't think of his name.
[SPEAKER_04]: I'm sure that Minnesota had the Rookie of the Year player.
[SPEAKER_04]: Wouldn't that be a feather in his cap, at 95, in his 95th year sending up the rookie of the year.
[SPEAKER_04]: That's his story right there.
[SPEAKER_04]: Wow.
[SPEAKER_04]: But then we've got to talk about the baseball camp.
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: So then he... You talk.
[SPEAKER_00]: In one of the stories he had, he gets up at 6.30 and eats his breakfast, then he goes out to the baseball camp every day.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was telling us we should go and see this stadium.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we said, all right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then he went and made a telephone call.
[SPEAKER_04]: And we had to go and see the stadium.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, oh, you can ride with us for getting.
[SPEAKER_00]: The way the back of the car was filled with all our camping gear and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: So the three of us scrunched up in the front seat, and everything that we carry in the front seat was dumped in the back.
[SPEAKER_04]: I thought you were getting awfully fresh.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mike puts on the accelerator almost.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we went out to the baseball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he took us back there and introduced us to the man who runs it, who is Wes Rinker.
[SPEAKER_04]: Rinker.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rinker.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wes Rinker.
[SPEAKER_04]: Forty-six years old.
[SPEAKER_04]: He played with the – he was in the Giants organization from 47 to 51 when he went to the service and came back.
[SPEAKER_04]: He played one year with the organization in 1956, then he went out of baseball.
[SPEAKER_04]: What he did from then on I don't know, but he came back about four years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where the Giants used to train?
[SPEAKER_04]: Yeah, the Giants.
[SPEAKER_04]: So he knew about Sanford.
[SPEAKER_04]: He knew about the town.
[SPEAKER_04]: What he had done, I wish I had asked him what he had done from 1956 to 1976.
[SPEAKER_04]: He came back here and he
[SPEAKER_04]: He had heard that the old Sanford ballpark, which the Giants had trained in, which I believe had a team in the Florida State League, was not used anymore.
[SPEAKER_04]: It was going to seed and being cluttered up with litter and so on.
[SPEAKER_04]: He had this idea of a baseball camp for boys.
[SPEAKER_04]: He came here four years ago and he spent some money.
[SPEAKER_04]: I'm quite sure he spent a lot of money cleaning that place up.
[SPEAKER_04]: He said there was, I don't know how many tons of broken glass and beer cans and other litter scattered throughout the high grass throughout the field.
[SPEAKER_04]: They got it all cleaned out.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's a beautiful layout today.
[SPEAKER_04]: And he said his office was an outhouse for blacks.
[SPEAKER_04]: It's a nice office now with a lot of